### **Daniel Evans**

Senior Service Manager - Digital, Data and Technology - Home Office

Daniel Liam Evans Mobile: 07512 671 852

8 Stratton Close **Email:** danny.evans@redwhitesky.uk

Wallasey Date of Birth: 25-01-1988 CH45 7SJ Nationality: British

#### PROFESSIONAL STATEMENT

I am a proactive technology professional with over 15 years' experience in the IT industry. My career spans multiple government departments including Crown Commercial Service and currently the Home Office.

Currently working in Service Management in Home Office' Digital, Data and Technology Directorate I work and embody the SIAM framework to deliver governance and assurance to IT Services in the Enterprise Live Service estate.

I value personal development. I currently hold both SIAM Foundation and ITIL v4 Foundation Certificates. I am currently working towards attaining ITIL Expert certification and to widen my experience and to continue to grow my skill set through personal and professional development into new opportunities and exciting challenges.

I have experience of working with industry standard technologies such as Windows, Windows Server Technology (including active directory, dns management and dhcp), CISCO products & services and VMware Virtual Infrastructure. In addition, I also have experience of working with cloud technologies such as Microsoft Azure and Amazon Web Services.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Senior Service Manager (*Temporary Cover to Lead Service Manager*) Home Office – Digital, Data and Technology

April 2019 – Present

Working at the Home Office in Digital, Data and Technology on the HM Passport Office Portfolio, I am responsible for ensuring that strategic services are delivered to the business by key partners in a cost-effective manner so that the best service is provided to the public.

# Digital Services Applications & Infrastructure Specialist Crown Commercial Service

July 2014 - April 2019

Managing and developing the organisations SalesForce environment. Building new functionality to help the business achieve its programme goals and maintaining current features to support business users, customers and suppliers.

Supporting the Delivery Programme by providing support and maintenance of infrastructure on Amazon Web Services and Microsoft Azure and providing technology and operational advice to the programme thought and beyond development.

Ensuring that the right IT infrastructure is in place to support the needs of the business, and that it is appropriately supported and maintained. Managing key Infrastructure Servers (Microsoft Exchange 2010/13, SQL Server 2008/12, SharePoint Server 2007). Evaluation, planning and implementation of infrastructure solutions to enable network connectivity for personnel at alternative office and home locations.

Other duties include but are not limited to; IT Service Provision (Infrastructure & Operation), Consultancy and Advice, IT Services Policy Development & Strategic IT Service.

## Curriculum Support & Instructor of GCSE Computing: Ridgeway High School Noctorum Avenue, Prenton, Wirral, CH43 9EB

May 2011 - July 2014

Responsibilities & Skills: During my time at Ridgeway I developed and delivered KS4 GCSE Computing scheme of work and facilitated in the teaching, learning and controlled assessment for the pupils GCSE certificate. Some of the key responsibilities in my job role included; planning, delivering and evaluating teaching and learning activities, preparing the classroom for lessons, helping pupils who need extra support to complete tasks individually and in groups, setting up information and communication technology (ICT) resources and supporting teaching and learning through the use of ICT.

I also developed a new system for the school to streamline end of term awards and certificates by developing a program and database the staff could use to award the pupils. As part of my third year project at university I will develop this system further to meet all of the need required by the school and in hopes that I may be able to package and sell the product to other schools.

Other responsibilities included: Web site development and maintenance, SIMS database management with speciality to Exams and Assessment Manager, IRIS Behaviour coordinator, biometrics coordinator, marketing and branding coordinator, technical systems consultant, year 11 work experience project management and assistance in the development of the ICT curriculum.

Office Administrator & Technical Assistant: Total ICT Ltd Yanco House Monks Ferry, Birkenhead, Merseyside CH41 5LH

October 2008 – April 2009

Responsibilities & Skills: Build, maintain and provide network support for clients, maintain company and customer backups, on call field engineer; onsite and via remote support and Sales & Marketing

Assistant Manager: Bobby's Bar Limited

1 Union Terrace, Marine Promenade, New Brighton, CH45 2JT

January 2006 – August 2008

Junior IT Consultant & Training Supervisor: Designated Associates Ltd 4 Park Road North, Birkenhead, Merseyside CH41 4EZ

June 2004 – July 2005

### **RECOMMENDATIONS**

## Juliette Glossop Director, Functional Consulting at Salesforce

I worked with Daniel for a Salesforce project. He was an absolute pleasure to work. Worked calmly, patiently and provided clear communication. He had picked up a lot of knowledge around the solution which meant the QA team could rely on him to answer their questions. I wish him all the best in the future and now he has gained his admin cert I can see him expanding his knowledge and capabilities of the platform

# Jim MacAulay Programme Architect at Salesforce

I have worked with Danny for the last year implementing and running a Salesforce instance. Although Danny had no previous Salesforce experience, he showed a true aptitude and picked it all up extremely quickly. He is very proactive, has a 'can do' attitude and is not afraid of new things. I very much enjoyed working with Danny and our regular debates as to which solution we should implement (though he was right more often than me). I would have no hesitation in recommending Danny to work on any technical project and would be happy to work alongside him again.

### Liverpool John Moores University (2010 to 2014)

### School of Computing and Mathematical Sciences, Byrom Street, Liverpool, L3 3AF

<u>BSc Computer Studies:</u> Software Development Project 2:1 (Hons) Classification Work Placement Evaluation

Business Systems: Analysis & Evolution

Network Security
Usability Engineering

Database Design and Connectivity
Personal and Professional Development

Principles of Computing and

Communication

Enterprise System Development Object Oriented Software

Development Development

Web Design

Introduction to Programming

Computing and Society Computers in Practice Computer Systems

#### Foundation Certificate:

Computer Studies: 2:1 Classification

West Cheshire College Chester Campus for Technology (2009 - 2010)

Eaton Road, Chester. CH4 7ER

BTEC National Award: Level 3 Software Development (Distinction)

South Wirral High School (1998 – 2004)

Plymyard Avenue, Eastham, Wirral.

GCSE: English Language (C), English Literature (C), Mathematics (C), Science Single Award (C),

Information Communication Technology (A)

#### **QUALIFICATIONS**

- SIAM Foundation
- ITIL v4 Foundation
- AWS Technical Essentials
- British Computer Society Professional Member
- SalesForce Administrator
- Microsoft Office Specialist 2010
- Level 3 Award in Education and Training
- Level 3 Award in First Aid at Work & Qualified First Aid Instructor

### **SKILLS PROFILE**

- Service Management
- Amazon Web Services
- Microsoft Azure
- Salesforce.com
- CISCO Systems
- Microsoft Network Infrastructure (Server, Domain Management and End User Technology)
- Microsoft Exchange
- VMWare
- VDI In-a-Box & HyperV
- Veeam
- Backup Exec
- EMC DataDomain
- Sophos Firewall & Mail Services
- McAfee EPO
- VoIP Telephony
- G-Suite